-= CHD字幕组 原创翻译 =-
字幕仅供翻译学习交流 谢绝用于任何商业用途
翻译：Victor zh7534268
校对：dahongying
21世纪末的地球面临人口过剩、环境污染及瘟疫流行的灾难
上层阶级逃离了这个星球以维持他们的生活方式
片名：极乐空间
麦克斯！
过来
别让其他人等着
她叫弗蕾
也是新来的
你识字吗？
Can you read?
这是长颈鹿
This is a giraffe.
它们生活在非洲
They lived in Africa.
- 你识字？   - 是的
- You can read? - Yes.
那里有很多的机器人保姆
There are many robot servers,
整天伺候你
and they serve you all day.
生活在那儿
If you live there,
你永远不会生病，变老
you'll never get sick, or old.
总有一天，我会带你去那儿的
I'll take us there, one day.
- 真的？   - 嗯，我保证
- Really? - Yes, I promise.
弗蕾和麦克斯
Frey and Max.
永远在一起
Forever.
麦克斯，你又偷东西了？
真是太伤我心了
为什么要偷？
为了攒钱？
买一张去极乐空间的船票？
那里不是你我去的地方
这不公平，嬷嬷
为什么我不能去？
生活中有很多东西是解释不清的
我们只有接受现实
但有一件事我很肯定
你是个很特别的孩子
有一天你会成大事
你天生就是这块料
我的孩子
洛杉矶  2154年
麦克斯，瞧瞧你！
Max, muy bueno!
上班去啦？
Off to work, huh?
早起的鸟儿才有虫吃啊
Gotta get up early, to work that line.
想让这个世界更美好吧？
Wanna make the world better?
你们可真搞笑，我有工作
That's real funny, I have a job.
可笑
Chistoso.
得了孩子们！你们觉得我有钱吗？
Por favor ninos! You think I got money?
我像是有钱人吗？
Do I look like I have money?
说你呢，赚了点小钱？
How about you, you got a little money?
快点，让我瞧瞧
Come on, whatta you got in there?
等等
Wait a minute.
是5块钱
Oh, it's 5 bucks.
等一会儿
Hey, wait a minute.
我赚了5元，我有钱啦
I got 5 bucks, I'm rich.
就能买去极乐空间的船票啦？
I can buy my ticket to Elysium, huh?
切
Alright.
请按次序排队
Please form an orderly queue.
公交车已到站
Your bus has arrived.
我身上没东西
I don't have anything.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
检查完毕，走吧
Checked. Move off.
早上好，警官
Morning, Officer.
您有犯罪前科
Extensive criminal history.
多项重罪
Multiple felonies.
袋子里装的什么？
What's in the bag?
主要是些护发产品
Hair products, mostly.
开个玩笑…
I'm just fucking with...
我只是去上班而已
I'm just going to work, man.
包里没东西
There's nothing in the fucking bag.
得了，我…
Come on, I...
不服从执法人员
Dealing with citizen disobedience.
我只是去上班，伙计，拜托
Just going to work, man. Come on.
- 检查完毕   - 跟你说没东西吧？
- Checked! - Nothing in it, is there?
预防犯罪，人人有责
Human tolerance policy applies to all citizens.
用你教我？
No shit?
您必须即刻向您的假释官报到
You must report immediately to your parole officer.
谢谢你的合作
Thank you, Citizen.
不，该谢您才是
No, thank you.
洛杉矶区医院
LOS ANGELES DISTRICT HOSPITAL
弗蕾，二床有骨折病人
Frey, fracture in bed 2.
麦克斯？
Max?
弗蕾…
Frey...
我还以为你在…
I thought you were...
什么时候回来的？
When did you get back?
有一阵子了
Been back for a while.
看来你还是没变化
I see things haven't changed.
不，我根本没干坏事
No, this wasn't even my fault.
- 是啊，让我看看你的伤  - 情况如何？
- Of course not. Let me have a look. - How's it?
伤得很严重
Pretty bad break.
现在你是护士了？
So you're a nurse, huh?
梦想成真啊！
You did it!
是啊
Yeah.
太好了
That's great.
你还在偷车吗？
You still stealing cars?
不，天哪，我再也没有做那种傻事了
No, God, I don't do any of that stupid shit anymore.
我在阿曼达因公司上班
I work at Armadyne.
生产线岗位，踏实干活…
On the line, you know? Workin...
弗蕾，三楼有病人去处理一下
Frey, they need you up on the 3rd floor.
马上就去
Be right there.
那么，既然你回来了…
So, you know, now that you're back...
等一下
Just a second.
Just sec.
多米妮卡，过来接一下好吗？
Dominica, can you take over here?
听着，因为你回来了，而且一切…
Hey, listen, because you're back and everyth...
麦克斯，很抱歉我都走了
Max, I'm so sorry I have to go.
见到你真好
Good to see you.
别再惹麻烦了
Stay outta trouble.
我没惹
I do.
你瞧…
Look...
我知道你为什么走，我理解
I know why you left the neighborhood, I understand.
要是我和你一样聪明，我也会走的
If I was as smart as you I would have left too.
和我吃个晚饭吧，就一会儿…
Have dinner with me. Just...
喝杯咖啡也行啊
I'll settle for a coffee.
- 不行   - 哦
- No. - Aww.
非得我弄折另一条胳膊才行吗？
Have I gotta break my other arm to get attention?
- 别说了  - 因为我真会这么干的
- Stop. - 'cause I will do that.
我的生活很复杂，麦克斯
My life is complicated, Max.
我只是，很…很想你
I just, I... I miss you.
我周三8点下班，行了吧？
My shift ends at 8 on Wednesday, OK?
好的，明白
Yeah, all right.
- 就喝咖啡   - 行，就喝咖啡，不干别的
- Coffee. - Yeah, coffee. Right.
现在走吧
Get out of here.
所有假释犯必须接受安检
All parolees must have weapons inspection
你好
Hello.
在开始之前，我想解释一下…
Before we start, I'd just like to explain...
麦克斯·达·柯斯达，今天在34-B号公交站
Max da Costa, violation of Penal Code 2219.
违反刑法第2219条
Today at bus stop 34-B.
没错，这正是我想和你说的
Yes, that's exactly what I wanted to talk to you about.
我相信这完全是个误会
See I believe there's been a misunderstanding.
假释期即刻延长八个月
Immediate extension of parole by a further 8 months.
等等，什么？不对，不对，我可以解释
Wait, What? No, no, I can explain what happened.
我只是看了个玩笑吧了，而且，你知道…
I just made a joke. And, you know...
别说了
Stop talking.
警官发现你有暴力的反社会行为
Police officer noted violent antisocial behavior.
很遗憾我们必须延长你的假释期
We regret that we must extend parole.
侦测到心率加快
Elevation in heart rate detected.
- 需要吃药吗？   - 不！
- Would you like a pill? - No!
谢谢，我想说的是…
Thank you, what I'd like to do is expl...
别说了
Stop talking.
人格分析显示您有78.3%的几率
Personality matrix suggests a 78.3% chance of
回归旧的行为模式：
regression to old behavior patterns:
如汽车盗窃
grand theft auto,
致命性武器攻击
assault with a deadly weapon,
拒捕…
resisting arrest....
你想和真人交谈吗？
Would you like to talk to a human?
不，我很好 谢谢
No, I'm OK. Thank you.
你是不是在讽刺或者骂我？
Are you being sarcastic and/or abusive?
不是
Negative.
辱骂假释官是重罪
It is a federal offense to abuse a Parole Officer.
了解
Understood.
达·柯斯达！你上班迟到了
Hey, Da Costa! You're late for your shift.
是的，头儿，遇到点小麻烦…
Yeah man, I had a little thing...
不，不，你这样可干不了活，你走吧
No, no. You can't work with that. You're out.
别，别，我很好，头儿，我能干活
No, no, I'm good, man. I can work.
石膏今天晚点就能拆了，我没事
It's coming off later today. I'm fine.
- 真的没事？   - 真的！
- You're good? - I'm good!
好吧，但得扣你半天工资
OK, I'm docking you half a day.
- 好吧，没事   - 你该庆幸还有活干
- Yeah, alright. - You're lucky to have this job.
未侦测到武器，准许进入
No weapons detected. You are clear for entry.
请保持车间整洁
Please keep your workstation tidy.
整洁的环境才能出高效的工作
A tidy workstation is an efficient workstation.
你看，老板喜欢上你啦
Hey check it out, man. I think he likes you.
他今天做过去角质术了？
Think he got his face peeled today?
看起来不错
He looks good.
注意：所有工人必须完成一周生产指标
Attention: all workers must reach weekly quotas.
请随时向主管人员汇报异常动向
Please report any unsafe activity to your supervisor.
如果我们没有明确的改进方式
If we don't have a clear path to up-side,
我们的投资人就会赔钱
our investors are going to start losing a lot of confidence.
你以为我来地球是干什么？
What do you think I've been doing here, on Earth?
你以为我喜欢来这里吸废气？
D'you think I enjoy breathing this air?
当然不是，但是…
No, of course, but...
我在尽一切可能…
I'm doing everything possible...
去为公司恢复盈利
to restore profitability to this company.
我一手创建的公司
The company that I built.
现在，如果你们不介意，
Now, if you will excuse me,
我必须暂停我们之间的对话了
I have to not speak to you people any longer.
谢谢
Thank you.
34号炉门关闭！
Closing 34!
34号炉开始烧制
Firing 34.
快把标签打上去！
Tag her quick!
动作快，我们没时间了
Let's go, we don't have much time.
我们破解了三组运输船密码，斯派德
We have 3 transporters codes, Spider.
好了，把它们放到屏幕上
OK, pull'em up on screen.
密码已接受
Codes have been accepted.
运输船点火！
Fire up the shuttles!
我们出发啦！
We're going up!
- 欢迎光临   - 你好，夫人
- Welcome. - Hello, ma'am.
- 去参观一下花园吧   - 会的，谢谢
- Take a look at the garden. - We will, thank you.
- 你好，德拉库特夫人   - 你好
- Hello, Madame Delacourt. - Hello.
你好，伊凡，瞧瞧你都长那么大啦
Hi, Ivan, how you've grown.
你好，还好吗？
Hi. You alright?
很好 孩子们都来了吗？
Fine. Are the kids here?
是的，和多米妮卡在一起呢
Yes, with Dominica.
我给你带了礼物 想看看吗？
I have a present for you. Wanna see?
在客厅呢
It's in the salon.
和你妈妈去看看吧
Go get it with your mother.
就在开胃小菜边上
It's, by the canape.
- 好的 - 再见
- OK.     - Bye.
夫人，需要来份点心吗？
Madam, would you care for a refreshment?
指令：取消！
Command: Cancel!
安全漏洞
航天船编码被窃
很抱歉打扰您，夫人
Sorry for disturbing you, ma'am.
我们发现几艘未登记飞船入境
We have a number of undocumented ships in-bound.
下午好，德拉库特国防部长
Good afternoon, Defense Secretary Delacourt.
三艘未登记飞船正进入极乐空间领空
3 undocumented ships are approaching Elysium airspace.
启动6号与7号紧急预案
Emergency orders 6 and 7 are now in effect
协议 22/B39…
Protocol 22/B39...
注意，不明飞船抵近
Attention, incoming vessels.
你正未经许可擅自闯入极乐空间领空
You have made unauthorized entry into Elysium airspace.
- 爸爸！   - 别怕！
- Dad! - It's okay!
我们将被迫立即采取措施
We will be forced to take immediate action
你们正非法闯入极乐空间领空
You are in violation of Elysium airspace.
常规警告没用
Standard warning didn't work.
距离15000公里，持续接近中…
15,000 Kilometers and closing...
现在怎么办，夫人？
What do you want us to do, ma'am?
让克鲁格行动
Activate Kruger.
夫人，根据第355号行政命令
Ma'am, according to Executive Order 355
我们无权启用在地球上的探员…
we are unauthorized to use our assets on earth...
我授权给你
I am authorizing you.
遵命，夫人
Yes, ma'am.
呼叫32号探员… 完毕
Agent 32... over.
数据传输中… 完毕
We are sending the packet... over.
欢迎，克鲁格探员！
Welcome, Agent Kruger!
10000公里接近中
10,000 Kilometers and closing.
把坐标数据传给他
Sending coordinates to asset.
目标数据：3个
Three target data.
把他们打下来！
Shoot them down!
准许发射，21-B，准许发射
Green light, 21-B. Green light.
导弹已发射！
Missiles away!
见鬼
Shit.
即将发生撞击，十…
Impacto inminente. 10...
八，七，六，五，四…
8, 7, 6, 5, 4...
三，二，一
3, 2, 1
两艘飞船已被击毁，46人死亡
Two ships destroyed. 46 total casualties.
准备撞击 5…
Impact in 5...
- 最后一枚导弹没有命中   - 荒唐！
- Last missile was a miss. - Ridiculous!
只剩下一艘了
Only one made it.
夫人，飞船已抵达大气层
Ma'am, the ship has breached our atmosphere.
飞船已着陆
First undocumented ship just touched down.
逮捕所有从飞船里出来的人
I want everyone coming out of that vehicle apprehendeded.
（公民 C.查韦斯 女性）
身份识别确认
Identification confirmed.
扫描中
Scanning.
多重综合性骨折
已检测
重建程序启动
Reconstruction process initiated.
不！
No!
32人被捕，13人死亡
We have 32 arrests, 13 casualties,
还有2个在逃，夫人
and 2 illegals at large, Ma'am.
重建完毕
Reconstruction complete.
你被捕了
You are under arrest.
根据不可移民法案第68条C款
Article 68-C Immigration Act.
- 所有非法移民已被扣押   - 很好
- All illegals are now in custody, ma'am. - Yes.
送他们去遣返处，驱逐出境
Send them to deportation, Get them off this habitat.
德拉库特部长
Secretary Delacourt,
请立即向帕特尔总统汇报
Please report to President Patel immediately.
德拉库特部长，请向帕特尔总统汇报
Secretary Delacourt, report to President Patel.
怎么了，伙计？
What up, man?
老样子，警察干的
Como siempre, the police, man
- 你没事吧？   - 没事，别担心
- Are you OK? - Yeah, don't worry about it.
麦克斯，我得和你谈谈，你知道…
Max, I gotta talk to you. You know...
- 不行！   - 你这是什么意思？
- No! - What do you mean no?
我都还没说什么事呢
You didn't even hear what I was gonna say.
- 好吧，你说   - 好的
- Alright, go ahead. - OK.
知道德赛塔在山上的房子吗？
You know the house of Doseta's up on the hill?
知道，戒备森严
Yeah, the one with all the guns.
没错，他们有五辆新车
Yeah, they have five cars. New ones.
我们偷三辆回来，明天午饭时间行动
It's gonna be three of us. Tomorrow, at lunch.
午饭时间？这就是你们的计划？
Lunch time? That's the plan?
我的老天爷
Jesus Christ.
你有更好的办法吗？
You have a better plan?
是的，就带一个人
Yeah, just take one guy.
天亮前出发，偷两辆最快的车
Go before sun comes up. You take two fastest cars.
其他的把电池破坏掉
Torch the batteries on the other ones.
见你的鬼，见鬼去吧！
Fuck you. Fuck you!
和你开玩笑啦！
I got you cojone!
求你了 你是高手
Oh please. You're the best.
帮我一年 就一年
Give me one year. Just one year.
我可不想再去坐牢
I'm not going back to prison.
就一年，拜托！
One year, please!
瞧瞧你！
Look at you!
当年你可是传奇人物，现在呢？
You used to be a legend, and now what?
北京时间，早上5:50分
The time is 5:50 am.
未侦测到武器，准许进入
No weapons detected. You are clear for entry.
34号炉门关闭！
Closing 34!
门禁故障
注意，炉门未关闭，请检查
Attention, doors are not aligned. Worker attend.
嘿，别偷懒
Hey, you're holding up the line.
不，我没有，门卡住了！
No, no, I got a jam!
注意：值班时使用厕所不得超过一次…
Attention: workers may not use the restroom more than once per sh...
你都干了什么把门弄坏了？
What've you done to close up?
没有，我在试着重启
No, I'm just trying to reset.
让我看看
Let me look.
- 卡到货板了   - 是啊，动不了了
- The pallet's pinched. - Yeah, It didn't move.
- 进去修好   - 不，我是指…
- Just go in there. - No, I mean...
听着，要么进去给我弄好…
Look, you go in there right now...
要么我找想弄的人来
or we'll find someone who will,
然后你走人
and you can go clean out your locker.
别这样，伙计
Come on, man.
就这样 你去修，明白？
Not. That's the deal, OK?
快去！
In you go!
加把劲，干活！
C'mon people, work!
见鬼
Fuck.
不，不，不，停下！
No, no, no, stop!
探测到有机组织 K-34
快点！去干活！
Come on! Go work!
来不及了！
Too late!
清场！
Extraction!
嬷嬷，他们打我
Sister, they beat me up.
我只想去那儿生活
I only want to live there.
从这里看那儿很美吧？
See how beautiful it looks to us down here?
是啊
Yes.
那么…
Well, now...
从那里看地球也很美
See how beautiful we look to them up there.
拿着
Keep this.
我把它给你
Now it belongs to you.
这样你就不会忘记你是从哪儿来的了
So you never forget where you come from.
什么情况？
What happened?
你遭到了致命辐射
You have been exposed to a lethal dose of radiation.
你的身体器官将会严重衰竭
You will experience catastrophic organ failure.
你会在五天之内死亡
In five days time, you will die.
发生什么事了？
What is going on?
为什么生产线停了？
Why has production stopped?
- 他被辐射了…   - 别对着我呼吸
- He's been exposed... - Don't breathe on me.
- 捂住你的嘴   - 对不起，老板
- Cover your mouth. - I'm sorry, sir.
他会脱皮之类的吗？
Does his skin fall off, or something?
我可不想把床换掉
I don't want to replace the bedding in there.
赶紧把他丢出去
Just get him out.
- 遵命，老板   - 很好，谢谢
- Yes, sir. - Right, thank you.
卡莱尔先生，您的飞船已经准备就绪
Mr. Carlyle, your shuttle is ready for departure.
请在药品接收单上签字
Please sign this to receive medication.
迈普龙… 药效很强
Miporol... extremely potent.
死前会维持你的身体机能运转
Will keep you functioning normally until your death.
配合三餐服用
Please take one pill with each meal.
感谢你的服务
Thank you for your service.
昨天下午三点
At 15:00 hours yesterday
你击落了两架飞船
you shot down two shuttles,
造成46人死亡
killing 46 civilians.
对于那些非法移民，你应该采取秘密措施
Your mandate is to deal with illegals 'quietly'.
我知道
I am aware of that.
你还启用这位探员
And then there's the use of this agent.
克鲁格探员
A Mr. M. Kruger.
15项侵犯人权指控…
15 human rights violations...
强奸，绑架，虐待
Rapes, kidnapping, torture.
这人被确诊有严重的精神问题
The man's been diagnosed with serious psychological issues.
我们已经明确向你表过态
We made explicitly clear to you
不再启用潜伏探员
that we're no longer using sleeper agents.
告诉我，帕特尔总统
Tell me something, President Patel.
你有孩子吗？
Do you have children?
我可不是接受质询的人
I'm not the one being reviewed here.
那我就假设你没有
Then I will assume you do not.
或许，如果你有孩子
Perhaps, if you did have children.
你就会觉得
Then you would behave in a manner
这样做有利于极乐空间的长久发展
that is more conducive to the longevity of this habitat.
我明白
I understand,
我的做事风格不是你们想要的那种
it is not the fashion to think and to act as I do.
我很明白
I understand that perfectly.
但当他们来抢你的房子时…
But when they come for your house...
或者你为你孩子建造的房子
or the house you built for your children.
和你子孙的房子时…
And your children's children...
什么公共关系和竞选承诺可阻止不了他们
It won't be PR or campaign promises that keep them out.
我能！
It will be me!
我听够了！这是给你的最后警告
I've heard enough! This is your final warning.
只要再有什么未授权的越界行为
Any further unauthorized actions,
你将会被清除出内阁
and you will be removed from office.
永久解除克鲁格的探员职务
And let's discharge this agent Kruger permanently.
全体通过吗？
All in favour?
很好 决议立即生效
Good. Effective immediately.
协议
代码更新
克鲁格探员已解职
想来点啤酒吗？
You want some beer?
你已被CCB解职
You have been discharged from CCB.
请把所有武器交还至当地大使馆
Please return all weapons to local embassy
去你的政客！去你的！
Fuck your 'Politikster'! Fuck you!
快看…
Look...
麦克斯…
Max...
麦克斯！
Max!
怎么了？出了什么事？
What's wrong? What happened?
天哪，我扶你，走吧
Jesus, let me help you. Let's go.
麦克斯，发生了什么事？
Max, what happened?
麦克斯，发生什么事了？
我就不该进去
I shouldn't have gone in it.
进哪儿去？
Gone in where?
我遭到了强辐射，伙计
I took a full dose, man.
致命剂量的
Lethal dose.
你还好吧？我来帮你
You OK? Let me help.
你会好起来的，麦克斯
You're gonna be OK, Max.
他们给了我一瓶药
They gave me Miporol, man.
就给了一瓶… 药
They gave me... Miporol.
我只剩五天活头啦！
I got five fucking days!
我只剩下五天了！
I only got five days!
你得吃药
You have to take this.
在极乐空间就能治好
They can fix this shit on Elysium, man.
我知道
I know.
- 我得去找斯派德  - 麦克斯，麦克斯！
- Gonna go see Spider. - Max, Max!
赶紧把药吃了！
Take the pill!
给你水！
There you go!
要见斯派德，得花钱
To see Spider, you need money.
就算搭上我的全部家当
I'll give you everything I have,
也买不起票啊
but it's not enough for a ticket.
他会给我票的
He's going to give me a ticket.
绝对会给我的
He's gonna give me a fucking ticket.
弗蕾，我们已经尽全力救治你的女儿了
Frey, you know we've done everything we could to help your daughter.
但是今天我和院方高层碰了头
But I had a meeting today with the board,
他们建议我把她送回家
and they're recommending that we send her home with you.
把她留在家里我还怎么工作？
How can I work here and leave it at home?
你清楚她的病随时会发作，法伊泽尔医生
You know it can happen anytime, Dr. Faizel.
我知道，如果她再突然发作
I know, if she has another seizure,
我们就把她送回家
of course bring her back here.
但到那个时候她就没救了
But until then she's discharged.
这里不是极乐空间
This isn't Elysium.
我们没办法治
We can't just heal her.
麦克斯！
Max!
好久不见啊，兄弟！
It's been a while, my brother!
上班的日子如何？
How's life at the factory?
我需要你帮个忙
I need to ask you a favour.
什么？我听不见 什么？
What? I can't hear you. What?
我需要一张票 去极乐空间
I need a ticket. Up there.
和一个身份证
And an ID.
行，没问题
Yeah, sure sure.
没说的，你想要过道的位置还是靠窗的？
Absolutely. You prefer aisle or window?
别耍我，我是认真的，伙计
Don't play games with me. I'm fucking serious, man.
听着，我会回来为你工作的
Listen, I'm gonna come back and work for you.
听凭差遣，我会还你钱的
Anything you need. I'll fucking pay it back.
知道吗？
You know what?
这… 可是…
This... is...
无价的
priceless.
这可是无价的
This is priceless.
让我问你个问题
Yeah, let me ask you a question.
你知道有多少蠢货
Do you have any idea how many idiots
跑到这里和我说着同样的话吗？
come in here saying the same kinda bullshit?
每天都有一群小屁孩儿过来找我
I got little kids coming here every day.
麦克斯，我要是你
Max, if I were you,
我会立刻滚出去
I'd get the fuck out of here, right now
我替你卖了3年命
I did 3 years for you.
整整3年
Everything I did for you,
你必须把我送上去
you're gonna get me up there.
开枪吧
Go ahead and shoot.
反正我已经被辐射了
I got so much radiation in my body, right now,
可能你也会被传染
you're probably getting a little sick yourself.
你真的快死了？
You really dying?
是的，你个杂碎
I'm fucking dying, motherfucker.
看到了吗？我把枪放下
See this? I put the gun down.
把枪放下！
Put the gun down!
都把枪放下！
出去！
Get out of here!
好吗！
Okay!
听着，我正在找人替我干一票
Listen, I've been looking for someone to take a job for me.
但这儿没人有那个胆量
But no one here has the balls.
你说你愿意干任何事，对吗？
You said you'd do anything, right?
麦克斯…
Max...
- 嘿   - 我没事
- Hey. - I'm OK.
这个…
This...
我的朋友
My friend.
这个就是你的票
This can be your ticket up there.
你替我干最后一票，我就帮你上去
One last job for me, You earn your way up.
是什么？
What is it?
抓一个极乐空间的混蛋，明白？
Take an Elysian asshole, right?
一个因为生意上的事来地球的亿万富翁…
A billionaire who's down on Earth for some business...
他是，是来这儿，管他干什么呢，我们绑了他
He's, he's here for, whatever. We hijack him.
- 得了吧！   - 放松
- Fuck that! - Relax.
这家伙可没那么简单
The guy's like much worse.
我们不抢表，不抢车，什么都不抢
Forget his watch, forget his ride, forget all that shit.
就抢这个
This, is what you take.
储存在他脑子里的有机信息
Organic Information, right out of his head.
我说的是银行代码
I'm talking about the bank codes,
密码，登陆数据…
passwords, login data...
能赚上千万
Access to billions.
你要做的就是把这个插入他的脑子里
All you have to do is plug into his brain,
下载数据到你脑子里…
download the data to yours with this baby...
然后带回来给我
And bring it to me.
这太疯狂了，麦克斯
This is crazy, Max.
一旦我们确认数据
Once we verify the data,
我就帮你上去
I'll give you a one way ride,
全部免费
all expenses paid.
还会附赠点心和饮料
Even throw in some snacks and a drink.
你要做的就是走到房子里
All you have to do is walk into a house
去找一张医疗床，然后你就痊愈了
and use the Med-bay, and you're cured.
桑德罗会给你做手术，你知道他吧？
Sandro who will do the surgery. You know him?
- 见鬼…  - 天哪！
- Fuck... - Christ!
我很好
I'm good.
老实说，你看起来太虚弱了
Actually, you seem all weak.
一团糟啊，那么…
And a fucked up, so...
知道吗？我有…
You know what? I have...
这太疯狂了，我们走吧
It's crazy, let's get out of here,
拜托，你就听我的吧
Please, listen to me.
我还有的选吗？
What am I gonna do?
我会让他们给你装上…
I'll have them install...
这玩意儿！
this!
第三代机械骨骼战甲
A third generation Axo-suit.
我们把它和你的神经系统连接起来
We hook this into your nervous system,
你就会变得和那些机器人一样强
and it'll make you as strong as a droid.
你已经蓄势待发了，对吧？
You're already under the knife, right?
我们走吧，求你了
Let's get out of here, please.
我要一个四人分队，人由我来挑
I want a 4 man team. But I pick them.
但得要有我的数据操作员
I'm sending my own data wrangler.
大脑传输，那可不是件轻松的事啊
Brain to brain, that is real tough.
行，但我要带上胡里奥
OK, but I'm taking Julio,
他也得要有一张票，和我一样
he gets a ticket up there, same as me.
可以，没问题
Yeah, sure.
好了，我去叫人准备
OK, I'll go get the boys ready.
等等！
Wait!
就绑约翰·卡莱尔
It's gotta be John Carlyle.
就是那个阿曼达因公司的首席执行官，卡莱尔？
The CEO of Armadyne, Carlyle?
就是他
That's the mark.
德拉库特部长，卡莱尔先生到了
Secretary Delacourt, Mr. Carlyle has arrived.
你来这儿是为了说服我
You are here to persuade me
和你们续签阿曼达因的合同的吧？
to renew our Armadyne contracts, yes?
您是个聪明人
Astute as always.
跟我来
Come with me.
我对你的小算盘不感兴趣
I'm not interested in your little ideas.
我只对“大生意”感兴趣
I am interested in something much larger.
这个地方正在走下坡路
This habitat is dying.
这里的领导层不行了
There is a political sickness inside of it.
这块“毒瘤”必须得切除
A tumor that needs to be removed.
你和你的公司所需要的利润正在枯竭
You and your company are in need of revenue that is drying up.
所以…
So...
既然是你建造的极乐空间
You built the Torus.
能否越过服务器
Can you override the servers
直接扶植一个新总统上台呢？
and place a new president in power?
政变？
A coup?
您是打算发动政变？
Are you suggesting a coup?
有可行性吗？
Is it possible?
我可以编写一段重启数列
I could write a reboot sequence.
它会关闭整个系统
It'd shut down the entire system,
到那时…
and at that point...
您就可以任命一个新总统了
you can encode a new President, yes.
那就赶紧去做吧
Then that is what you will do.
而且接下来200年的合同就全都是你的了
And you will have your contract secured for the next 200 years.
导弹防御电池，机器人
Missile Defense Batteries, Droids,
所有的一切，来保卫自由
everything we need, to protect our liberty.
当然，新总统会兑现承诺的
All guaranteed, of course, by your new President.
去吧！着手进行吧，卡莱尔先生
Go! Get to work, Mr. Carlyle.
就是那个家伙
This is the guy.
- 就是他？   - 就是他
- He's the guy? - This is him.
坐下
Sit down.
我们会治好你的，宝贝儿
We're gonna cut you up good, homie.
小心点儿，朋友，小心
Play nice, amigo. Play nice.
先给他标上身份证
Let's get him an ID first.
一组身份代码
one of them identification codes.
准备好
Get that ready.
胳膊抬起来
Arm up.
它会和你的DNA结合
It'll merge with your DNA.
这样你就成合法公民了
Now you fit in.
就像在那儿出生的一样
Like you were born there
现在好戏开场了
Now it's time for the real fun.
把它给我
Lower it to me.
嘿，伙计
Hey, man.
会疼吗？
This gonna hurt?
没错，会疼
Yeah bitch, it's gonna hurt.
但是不会很疼
It's gonna hurt good.
等我们完事儿了
When we're done with you,
你就成忍者了
you're gonna be a ninja.
玛丽安娜…
Mariana!...
把骨锯给我！
Bring down the bone saw!
这伤不了我
This ain't gonna kill me.
你不会有事的，不会的
You'll be airight. Not bad.
麦克斯
Max.
我就在这儿
I'm here.
我们能做到的，兄弟
We got this, man.
能吗？
We got this?
能！
Yeah!
他醒了！
He's awake!
成功了？
Made it, huh?
真意外！
Surprised!
你还能继续打飞机呢
You can still jack off, alright?
进展如何？
How's everything going?
一切顺利
Ready to kick ass?
你都对我干了些什么？
What the fuck did you do to me?
给你条活路
Gave you a way out.
协议重启
正在编译
序列完成
想要保护这个数据吗？
是              否
选项A  关闭
选项B  致死
准备往大脑传送
怎么样，兄弟？
What's up, partner?
穿着战甲的感觉如何？
How's that suit working out for you?
有点紧
That shit is tight!
给我看看武器
Show me.
拿着
Hold this.
这是祖传宝贝吗？
Is this a family heirloom?
等等
Wait for it.
空爆弹头
Air-bursting ammunition.
自动锁定目标…
Designate your enemy...
每发子弹都能对半径5米内的目标造成杀伤
and any round you fire will explode around a 5 meter kill radius
还有…
And...
这支配备遥控爆破弹药，威力巨大
Safe Detonation rounds for this bad boy.
嗯，不错
That'll work.
出发！
Move out!
先生…
Sir...
您的飞船准备好了
Your shuttle is ready.
卡莱尔：我已出发
收到了吗？
Do you read me?
是
Yes
好了，计划是这样的
Alright, here's the deal.
我们会埋伏在厂外面
We'll wait outside the factory
直到看见飞船离开
until we see the shuttle leave.
你们其中的一个先把弹头射进船体
One of you will shoot a round in it
我们再赶去坠落点取数据
then we go to the crash site and get some data.
好的，收到
OK, copy that.
摄像头启动，小子们
Be back in five, boys.
好了，我们出发，好戏开始！
Alright now, let's go! Let's play ball!
紧张吗？
You nervous?
-不   - 真的？
- No. - No?
我怕得要死
I'm shitting myself with fear.
- 我们会成功的   - 是的
- I'm not gonna fucking die. - No.
行动！
Go, go, go!
15秒内加速至超音速
Acceleration to supersonic speed in 15 seconds.
动作快，快点！
Come on, come on!
临界发动机故障
Critical engine failure.
夫人，有极乐空间公民在地球遇到危险
Ma'am, we have an Elysium citizen on Earth in danger.
数据提取中…
Data coming up now...
公民身份验证
Citizen identified.
约翰·卡莱尔 编号N8321…
John Carlyle. N8321...
看到你啦，混蛋！
I see you, motherfucker!
紧急情况
I have a situation here.
克鲁格，收到了吗？
Kruger, do you read me?
德拉库特女士
Ah, Ms Delacourt.
听到您的声音可真高兴啊
How lovely to hear your voice.
有一位携带敏感资料的公民
There's a citizen carrying sensitive brain data
正在城外
out of the city right now.
那些小偷想要绑架他
Some thieves are trying to hijack it.
什么资料？
What's in it?
这是机密
That's classified
你不能叫一个刚被开除的探员
You don't call a recently deactivated agent
去取回机密信息！
to retreive classified fucking information!
政府还不知道此事吧？
The government doesn't know about this, do they?
这么说来我可以漫天要价了，对吧？
I can ask for whatever I want, can't I?
地面撞击准备
Prepare for impact
请保持镇定，您没有受伤
Please remain calm. You have sustained zero injuries
哦，那敢情好
Oh, that's a real comfort.
我有一个条件：
I got one condition:
我帮你取回数据，你帮我复职
I do this, I get re-instated
成交
Fine.
我已经重新派遣了两位你的得力干将
I've recommissioned 2 of your preferred agents.
当然是完全保密的
Completely confidentially, of course.
他们现在应该到了…
They should be at your position any second...
告诉我任务内容吧
Feed me the mission data
加油，伙计们，快下车
Come on, guys. out of the car!
警卫，有不明轮式车出现，有一个…
Droids, there appears to be some type of wheeled vehicle, with one...
两个人下车了
Two occupants.
他们全副武装，消灭他们
They are armed and I'd like them dead.
机器警卫！
Droid!
卡壳了！
Jammed!
身份鉴别，麦克斯·达·科斯塔
Identified, Max da Costa.
联邦假释号：61492-8-557
Federal Parole number 61492-8-557
枪卡壳了！
It's jammed, man!
搞定了！
Got it!
他在重新装弹！
He's reloading!
伙计们！我们干掉他了！
Guys! We got the bastard!
前进！我掩护你！
Go! I got you covered!
前进！
Go, go, go!
别乱动
Don't fucking move.
准备数据传输！
Bring it!
还有另外一个！
Another one!
去死吧，混蛋！
Die, motherfucker!
别伤到人质！
Don't hit the mark!
不，不！他被打中了！
No, no! He got hit!
公民遭受胸部外伤
Citizen has sustained a cardio-thoracic trauma.
血压降低
Blood pressure is dropping
头部没事！
Not in the head!
胸部也没事！
No in the chest!
扶住他的头，让我看看
Hold his head, let me see.
让我看看你的头
Let me see your brain.
快点，快点！
Come on, Come on!
- 好了   - 有反应了吗？
- Yes. - Is it working?
是的，正在同步
Yeah, we're syncing.
你根本就没意识到你在干什么
You have no idea what you're doing.
距离目标一分钟，长官
One minute to target, sir.
数据正在同步，加油啊，加把劲儿
We're syncing. Come on, baby, here we go.
成了！传输开始了
It's gonna work. We got it
发现数据截留，夫人，他们正在下载
It's a data heist, ma'am. They're downloading now.
伙计们，我们有伴儿了
Guys, we've got in-coming.
见鬼！
Fuck me!
加油啊，伙计们，快点
Come on, guys, hurry up.
那是掠夺者飞船，军用的
That's a Raven. That's Military.
马上就好了，97…98！
Alright we got this, 97...98!
快点，他们就要来啦
Hurry up, they're coming.
- 马上就好了！ - 99！
- Almost there! - 99!
完成！读取中！
In! Here we go!
见鬼！数据肯定被破坏了！
Shit! Data must be corrupted!
怎么回事…？这是什么情况？
What the f...? What does that mean?
等等，等一下
Wait. Hold on.
我无法读取数据 扰频了！
I can't read the data. It's scrambled!
无法读取！
I can't read the data.
什么？
What?
伙计们！我们得走了！
Come on, guys! We gotta move!
“扰频”是什么个意思？
What the fuck does 'scrambled' mean?
我靠
Fuck this!
别，别！再跑一次！再跑一次！
No, No! Run it again! Another time!
放手，我得走了！
Get off me, man! I'm bailing!
拜托，再来一次啊
Please. Run it again.
该死的 我们快走
Fuck you! Let's get out of here.
你在搞什么，桑德罗？
What the fuck are you doing, Sandro?
快离开这里！可恶！
Let's get outta here! Goddammit!
快走
C'mon man
离开那！快走！
Get out of there! Let's go!
我们得走了！快点啊！！
We gotta go! Come on! Come on!
头儿，有人要逃跑
Hey, boss, we got a runner.
开火！
Fire!
这就对了！
That's what I'm talking about!
去你的！
Fuck, man!
目标正在由南向西南移动
Target moving south-southwest
快走！
Move back!
又发现一个
We got another one.
再来一次！
Again!
这下完了！这下全完了！
This is wrong! This is all wrong, man!
进入盘旋模式！
Going into holding pattern, sir!
你认为能逃到哪？
Where do you think you're going?
可恶！
Fuck!
Motherfucker!
来啊！
Come on!
不！
No!
不，不！
No, no!
不！快起来！
No! Get up!
起来啊！
Get up!
不！
No!
一名反抗者正在徒步逃跑
We've got one assailant leaving on foot, ma'am.
他们有数据
They have the data.
重复：这些罪犯有数据
Repeat: The thieves have the data.
不惜一切代价抓住他
Apprehend the target at all costs.
但不要损坏他的大脑
Do not damage his brain.
走吧！去抓住那家伙
Let's go! We got a runner, boy!
这个公民失血过多
The citizen has suffered catastrophic blood loss
导致心跳停止
leading to cardiac arrest
死亡时间，17点45分
Time of death, 17:45.
出来吧，你藏哪了
Come on, where are you hiding?
那是什么？
What's that?
看上去像是猪
Looks like a herd of pigs, boss.
可恶，找到他
Fuck you, man! Find him!
去坠机地点，看看留下什么线索
Go back to the crash site, see what they left behind.
收到
Roger, that.
谢了，婆婆
Thanks ma'am.
头儿，我想你最好过来看下
Hey boss, I think you better come look at this.
这是我们截获的
This is a record of what we picked up
卡莱尔和逃犯之间的传输记录
being transferred between Carlyle and the criminals.
难怪她如此想要追回来
That's why she wants it so badly.
他脑子里有开启极乐世界的钥匙
He's got the keys to the kingdom in his fucking head!
现在，我们只需要找到他
Now we just need to find it.
释放飞碟
Gonna let the girls out.
搜寻3到11路
13 grid, 3 to 11.
我下令封锁全区
I'm authorising a Full Containment Order.
洛杉矶禁飞
Issue a No Fly Zone for Los Angeles.
全洛杉矶？
All of Los Angeles?
罪犯正在逃亡
The murderer's still out there.
直到找到他
Until we apprehend him,
否则全洛杉矶不能有任何人离开
No one leaves the surface of that city.
搞什么…？
What the f...?
麦克斯
Max.
宝贝！
Hey, sweety!
我们能回家了
We can go home.
我好点了吗？
Am I better?
我去开车，好吗？
I'm gonna get the car, okay?
马上回来
Be right back.
弗蕾…
Frey...
麦克斯
Max!
我的天哪，你怎么了？
My God, what happened to you?
- 该死，我去叫医生  - 不，不！
- Shit, gonna get the medics. - No, no!
- 我不能进去  - 麦克斯！
- I can't go in there. - Max!
我进不去…
I can't go in...
麦克斯，听着，你需要看医生
Max, listen, you need a doctor, OK?
他们再找我 他们要杀了我
People are looking for me. They're gonna kill me.
- 我到这来找你 你得帮我  - 麦克斯！
- I came here for you. I need your help. - Max!
你必须去医院接受治疗
You've got to go through the system to get treatment.
拜托你帮我，我还不想死
Please help me. I don't wanna die.
麦克斯！
Max!
醒醒！
Stay awake!
我想看看那个人
I wanna see the man.
妈妈去帮他，好吗？
Mama's gonna help him, OK?
你先睡吧
Try to sleep.
别睡着！
Don't sleep!
你可真够重的
You're too heavy for me.
麦克斯，帮帮我！
Max, help me!
加油！
Come on!
麦克斯，你行的，加油！
Max, you can do it, come on!
等会，我先把你转过来！
No, wait. Let's turn you over!
麦克斯，等下
Max, Max, wait.
- 谢谢  - 谁把你弄成这样？
- Thank you. - Who did this to you?
好吧，我在工作时受到了感染
Okay. I got hurt at at work.
我只有接受斯派德的工作
I had to take a job from Spider
设法上极乐空间去得到治疗
to try to get up there and get healed.
结果失败了，现在我有麻烦了
It went bad, now I'm in trouble.
妈妈？
Mommy?
宝贝，到这来！
Hey, sweety, come here!
找个人是谁？
Who is that man?
他叫麦克斯
His name is Max.
我和你这么大的时候认识他的
Mommy knew him when he was your age.
这是玛蒂尔达
It's Matilda.
你去看动画片吧
You can go watch cartoons, OK?
我一会就过去
I'll be right there.
我并不知道你已经有…
I didn't know you had...
我很抱歉，我得走了
I'm so sorry, I need to go.
等下，麦克斯，你不能离开这
Wait, Max, you can not leave.
我不该来这，我得走了！
I shouldn't have come here. I have to leave!
麦克斯！她快死了
Max! She's dying.
白血病晚期
She's in the final stages of leukemia.
我说过我的人生很坎坷
I told you my life complicated.
我需要你的帮助
I need you to help me.
我不知道怎么办？
I've no idea how to do this.
干什么？
How to do what?
带他去极乐世界
Get her to Elysium.
我不能帮他 我…
I can't help her. I...
如果我能我当然会.
I would if I could.
这个呢？假的身份
How about this? Fake citizenship.
如果你带她去那里
If you took her there,
你能带她去那吗？
could you heal her with this?
这不可能
It doesn't work that way.
这个代码是和我的DNA锁在一块的
This is coded to me, it's locked to my DNA.
那些人正在找我 他们…
The people looking for me. They...
你不了解他们是什么样的人
You don't understand who these people are.
如果他们在这找到我，他们会杀光我们
If they find me here, they will kill all of us.
我唯一能帮你的就是离开这里
The only thing I can do to help you is leave.
我保证
I promise you.
她是我的全部
She's all I have.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你身上绑着绷带
You have bandages.
是，我绑着绷带
Yeah. I got bandages.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
我不想你生病
I don't want you to be sick.
你想听故事吗？
You wanna hear a story?
从前，有一只狸住在森林里面
There once was a meerkat who lived in the jungle.
它很饿，而且它很小
He was hungry and he was small.
非常的小
So small.
其他大的动物都有食物
And the other big animals had all the food,
因为他们可以够到水果
'cause they could reach the fruits.
所以它和一个河马当了朋友
So he made friends with a hippopotamus
好了，别说了
OK, stop!
关于狸的故事还没好的下场
It doesn't end well for the meerkat.
对，它站在河马的背上
Yes, it does 'cause he can stand on the hippopotamus' back
可以吃到它想吃的所有水果
to get all the fruits that he wants.
它给河马什么好处？
What's in it for the hippo?
这个河马想要一个朋友
The hippo wants a friend.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
头儿
Hey, boss.
我想我找到他了
I think we got him.
降落飞船
Yank this fucking boat!
妈妈，一切都好吗？
Mommy, is everything OK?
是的，宝贝
It's OK, sweety.
安全
Clear!
这是什么？
What is this?
下午好
Good afternoon.
很抱歉闯进你家 不是有意…
Sorry to come bursting into your home. Didn't mean to...
吓着你女儿
traumatize your young daughter.
我们正在找一个年轻的家伙…
Me and the boys here are looking for a young gentleman...
他之前还在这
who was in this very house a moment ago.
我希望你能告诉我他去哪了
We're hoping you can tell us where he went.
不
No.
我…
I...
我不知道他去哪了
I don't know where he is.
我不想…
I don't believe in...
在小孩面前用暴力
committing violent acts in front of the kids.
所以我需要你闭上你的眼睛
So I just need you to close your eyes, sweetheart.
没事
It's OK.
我真需要你告诉我
I really need you to tell me.
- 想起来了吗？ - 妈妈！
- You remember now? - Mommy!
闭上眼睛，捂住她的眼
Close your eyes, keep your fucking eyes closed.
让她闭上眼
Keep her eyes closed.
求你了，我真不知道他去哪了
Please, I don't know where he is.
他受伤了，我帮他治疗，之后就离开了
He was wounded, I helped him and he left.
拜托
Please!
你听到了吗？
D'you fucking hear that?
现在已经没有忠诚了吗？
No loyalty nowadays, hey?
这是什么？
What's this here?
这是你的医院？
This a hospital you're running here?
她病了
She's sick.
她病了？
She's sick?
让我看看她…
Let me have a look at her...
别碰她
Don't touch her.
看见了吗？母亲的本能保护！
See that? Protective instinct, here!
我说过了，别碰她！
I said don't touch her!
我看看能不能在你孩子口里套出话
I'm just trying to have a word with your child.
别碰她！
Do not touch her!
带她走
Bring her. Come!
你要带她去哪？
Where are you taking her?
宝贝，没事的
Sweety, it's OK.
没事，没事的
It's OK, darling. It's OK.
坐下！闭嘴！
Sit! Shut up!
停下！
Stop!
别，别，别开枪！
No, no, don't shoot him!
把枪放下！让他进来！
Put the gun down! Let him come!
你下载了一下数据，知道吗？
You got something, didn't you?
什么？
What?
这就是他们禁飞的原因…
That's why they shut down the sky...
是什么？
what is it?
转账资料？公司机密？
Wire transfers? Corporate intel?
你肯定搞到了重要资料！
You gotta have something big in there!
不 我们弄不到任何东西！
No. I fucking got nothing, man!
全是扰频 胡里奥死了
It all got scrambled. Julio is dead.
你欠我的 现在让我马上走！
You owe me. Let's go fucking now!
不行！飞行系统被他们锁定了！
We can't! The flight system is jammed!
没人能离开这
Nobody is going up there.
- 到什么时候？  - 我不知道
- Until when? - Till I don't fucking know.
我得离开这！
I gotta fucking get up there!
所有人都想离开这
Everyone needs to get up there.
我的人已经再想办法了
My guys are working on it.
我认为可能再也连不上线了
See if they have a hope in hell of ever getting back online.
但现在…
But, for now...
看看你脑袋里面到底是什么
Let's just take a look at that head of yours.
离我远点！
Get away from me, man!
看着我
Look at me,
他们关闭了整个天空
if they shut down the whole fucking sky,
就因为有什么在你脑袋里…
for what's in your head...
或许打开它的钥匙
Maybe the key to opening it
就在里面，对吧？
could be in there too, right?
过来
Come on.
好
Alright
为了这个他们会追杀你到天涯海角的
They will hunt you to the edge of the world for this.
这是什么？
What is it?
这是极乐世界的重启系统
It is a reboot program for Elysium.
谁拥有了它
Whoever has this,
就相当于有权利控制整个系统
has the power to override their whole system.
开放边界…
Open the borders...
所有人将成为极乐世界的公民
Make everyone a citizen of Elysium.
这也能救你的命
This can save your life.
我们能够拯救所有人
We can save everyone.
我什么时候去？
When can I go?
他们正在尝试黑进去关闭信号阻挡，应该不久…
They're trying to hack through the signal jam, but soon...
别说没用的，我们什么时候能走？
Don't bullshit me, when can we go?
我不知道
I dunno.
五天… 一周？
Five days... a week?
去你的，我没有5天了！
Fuck you, I don't have 5 days!
我没有时间了
I got hours.
我的人正在努力进去
My guys are working on it.
你总这么说
You're always working on it,
你不让我上去
You can't get me up there.
我不懂你为什么把人们弄上去
I don't know why you try sending people up there,
他们去了就是去送死
they just get fucking shot down.
有你脑袋里的东西就不会了！
Not with what's in your head!
这就是我要说的！
That's what I'm talking about!
我们将会控制这个系统
We would control the system.
我们将说了算！
We would be in charge!
我们甚至能改变这该死的历史！
We can change the course of fucking history!
回到刚才说的…
Back up there...
我脑袋里面的东西
What I have in my head,
对他们很重要，对吧？
is worth a lot to them, right?
不要这么做
Don't do this.
如果这落到他们的手里
If it falls into the wrong hands,
他们永远不会让我们进去的
they could shut us out for good.
听我说，我现在就上去
Listen, man, I'm going up there right now.
如果你找到我，而且我被治好了
If you can find me, and I'm healed,
我把一切给你
you can have all of this.
但我现在不想死
But I'm not fucking dying.
这不对，麦克斯，别这么做
This is wrong, Max, don't do this.
别开枪！
Do not shoot him! Do not shoot him!
让他走！
Let go!
没事，没事
It's okay. It's okay.
我一直想要个老婆
I always wanted a wife.
只是不能安定下来，你知道吗？
Just couldn't quite settle down, you know?
诱惑太多了
Too much temptation.
但你…
But you...
你让我想安家了
You make me ready to settle down.
你真的让我想安家了，宝贝
You really make me want to settle down, baby.
- 见鬼了，头 - 呃？
- Holy shit, sir. - Eh?
你最好过来看看
You better come take a look at this.
- 怎么了？  - 看看这个家伙
- What is it? - Check this fucking guy.
转头回去
Turn us around.
- 拿着它  - 好的，头
- Take it. - Right, sir.
开开门
Open the door.
站在那
Stop right there,
你在照我说说的做
and you're gonna do exactly what I say.
或者我将炸开我的头，明白了吗？
Or I'm gonna blow my fucking head off, understand?
好！
Yeah!
你能得到我脑袋里的一切东西！
You can have everything in my head!
只要你带我上去
Just take me up there,
并让我进医疗舱
and get me in a med-bay.
我的东西很有价值
What I have is very valuable.
我们能治好你
We can fix you up.
把你放进医疗舱，这些问题都好解决
Put you in a med-bay, Sort all this fuck-up.
走吧！我们带你上去
Let's go! We'll take you up there.
晴朗的天气，清新的空气
Weather's nice, air's nice and clean.
你将会喜欢那的
Likely you'll dig it.
别想其他的事！
Don't you fucking try anything!
上船吧！
Step aboard!
进来看看我们的兄弟，来吧
Come meet the boys, come on!
别害羞，他们吃不了你
Don't be shy, they won't bite.
我给你介绍
Let me introduce you.
这是德雷克 这是麦克斯
This is Drakie. This is Max.
怎么样？
What is news?
走吧！
Let's fly!
是的，夫人.我们已经抓到罪犯
Yes, ma'am, we apprehended the subject.
打开领空，我们要进去
Open the skies, we're coming in.
我们十九分钟后见
I'll expect you in 19 minutes.
取消禁飞
Cancel the No Fly Zone.
是的，夫人
Yes, ma'am.
连上…
Hold it...
连上了 怎么了？
Hold it. What is that?
网络连上了？马塞洛！
Are we back? Marcelo!
怎么回事？恢复了？
What the fuck is that? Are we back?
- 我们都连上了  - 好
- We're back online. - Alright.
弗蕾…
Frey...
我们抱歉
I'm sorry.
我能搞定这一切
I'm gonna make this right.
我们找到他了
We've got him.
好的 他在哪？
Alright. Where is he?
正在离开地球…
Leaving Earth...
去往极乐世界
Heading to Elysium.
曼纽尔！里克！拿上武器
Manuel! Rico! Get weapons!
我们上去
Let's get up there.
234号请求在22区着落
Echo leader 234, requesting landing in sector 22.
收到234号请求
Roger that Echo leader 234.
允许234号进入…
You are clear for entry...
我看你有G-1手雷
I see you got the G-1 there.
赶紧后退！
Hey, back the fuck up!
- 不然呢？ - 我会引爆他
- Or what? - I'll let it go.
你想干什么？
What you gonna do? Huh?
我们只是要你的脑袋里面的东西
I want what's in your head, boy. Git'im!
抓住甲板！
Grab'im Deck!
警报
第五扇区轨道受损
我们该怎么办.夫人
What do you want us to do, ma'am?
我想让国土安全局逮捕所有里面出来的人
I want everyone coming out of that vehicle apprehended by Homeland Security.
把安全级别五级以下的人
Evacuate everyone on the level five
全都请出这栋楼，快
clearence out of the building, now.
我警告过你
I warned you of this.
一艘无照的飞船坠毁
An unlicenced vehicle just crashed
对这里是潜在威胁
potentially damaging the Torus.
全都归咎于你的无能
All because of your inability to act.
把他带出去
Evacuate him.
别你的手拿开
Get your hands off me.
这属于战争行动
This is an act of war.
CCB现在由我来控制
That puts CCB under my control.
好，我来接管你的工作
Now, if you'll let me do my job.
我想你是不是该去参加个募捐活动
I'm sure you have fund raisers to attend.
走吧，先生
Let's go, sir.
麦克斯！
Max!
把我弄下来，麦克斯！
Take me out of here, Max!
我正在试！
I'm trying!
空气质量到底中毒水平
Air quality reaching toxic levels
把我弄下来！
Get me out of here!
建议你尽快离开这艘船
It is recommended you exit the craft immediately
跑啊！
Run!
去你的！
Fuck!
两个非法公民在第三区正在向东北方向逃窜
2 Illegals heading Northeast in zone 3
你去抓那两个 我来对付他
You deal with those two. I'll handle this pussy.
欢迎光临这栋别墅…
Welcome to the spectacular properties from your...
错误
Error
不！
No!
未识别公民身份
No citizens detected
求你了，她生病了，帮帮他
Please she's sick, help her.
她已经晕过去了
She's gone into a coma.
拜托了！
Please!
我们该不该弄掉这些东西？
Shouldn't we remove this thing?
不行，得到我们得到数据
Can't, till we get all the data.
这些和他的神经系统连接在一起
It's wired into him neurologically.
这些数据没有受损吧？
The data is intact, yes?
数据看起来完整的
Data looks intact.
警告
Warning
我们弄出来这些数据
We can still pull this data out of him,
那会杀了他
which will kill him.
没问题
Oh, it's fine.
你恢复系统，下载数据要多久？
How long before you can download and turn the system online?
不用很久，夫人
Not long, Ma'am.
把所有数据放在机密云里面
Keep everything in a restricted cloud.
禁止访问
Lock down all access.
马上开始
Starting prep right now.
把那两个弄出去
And get these two out of here.
好的
Roger that.
科特，你想去抓头的女人吗？
Kurt, you wanna go get the boss' chicks?
好啊
Yeah, good.
接近警告
一不明飞行器正在靠近
他们到处隐蔽
Give them the runaround.
让他们忙乎忙活
Keep them busy.
找到了！
Got 'im!
走吧！
Let's go!
好了 50字节，伙计
Alright. 50 exabytes, buddy.
准备好了吗？
Are you ready?
你们想在他那取出什么？
What are you taking out of him?
你们对他做了什么？
What're you doing to him?
他会怎么样？
What's gonna happen to him?
该起床了
Rise and shine.
- 起来！ - 麦克斯
- Get up! - Max.
麦克斯 麦克斯！
Max. Max. Max!
进去！
Get in there!
头被毁容了？
Yes. Boss got fucked up, eh?
吃了个手雷
Ate that fucking grenade, eh!
（脑功能正常）
他的大脑是好的
His brain is fine.
（已检测到颌面撕裂伤）
不过他醒了一定会气疯的
But he's gonna be pissed when he wakes up.
记得在印度，他丢掉了条胳膊吗？
Remember what cock-up happened in India when he lost his hat?
面部重建
克鲁格
Kruger.
头儿？
Boss?
我是克罗
It's Crowe.
他在哪？
Where is he?
好了，一切就绪
All right, all set.
我们可以获取数据了
Let's get the data.
准备注射
I got the needle prepped.
你抓住这个
You wanna grab this?
抓住针头！抓住…
Grab the needle! Grab the...
你们把她们带去哪了？
Where did they take the girls?
在储备库
The Armory.
那是哪？
Where the fuck is that?
在三层
Level three.
检测到致命病毒
Lethal radiation poisoning detected.
你需要立即接受治疗
You require urgent medical attention
你个蠢货！
You idiot!
你知道你在干嘛吗？
Do you realize what you've done?
你在郊区坠毁了一艘无证飞船
You crashed an unlicensed vehicle into a suburban area.
你的命令是机密行动
Your orders were to keep this covert.
你知道这是什么意思吗？
Do you even remember what that means?
你是不是完全疯了？
Have you completely lost your mind?
你已经没用了
You're useless to me.
如果政府意识到我们在做什么
If the administration realized what we're doing.
他们会把我们以叛国罪杀死
They'd hang us both for treason.
天哪，克鲁格！
For God's sake, Kruger!
听见了吗？
Are you listening to me?
是的
Yes.
是的，夫人
Yes, ma'am.
我听着呢
I'm listening.
我很抱歉我们飞船坠毁了
I'm sorry that we crashed the vehicle
破坏了别人的草坪
and ruined someone's lawn.
没人能以叛国罪杀死我们
But nobody is gonna hang us for treason.
我们现在说了算！
We do the hanging!
把手放在上面，按住
Put your hand on it. keep pressure on it.
不能说话了吗？
How tough you be now, eh?
好了，伙计们极乐世界总算可以有个称职的总统了
Right boys, Elysium is about to get its first proper president.
她需要一些治疗
She needs some medical attention.
我本来想治好你女儿的
I was gonna heal your daughter.
但现在，她永远不可能被治好了
But now, I'll make sure she's never healed.
德雷克，不要相信任何政客说的话
Drakie, don't trust any of those politicians!
清空这栋楼
Clear out this whole building!
好的，头
Thank you, boss.
我去找那个小混混
I'm gonna find that little gangster.
我将去下他的脑袋
I'm gonna take what's in his head.
现在这是我的了
This place is mine now.
你想来我家和我玩？
You want to come to my fucking house and play?
来玩吧
Then play!
我去干掉那个家伙
I'm going to annihilate that little motherfucker
把他碾成粉末…
Pulverize that damn...
发什么什么情况？
What the hell was that?
所有CCB成员请在最近的出口撤离
All members of CCB please go to the nearest exit
去底层…
and proceed calmly to...
走，快走
Go, go, go!
不
No.
确认死亡
Detecting deceased
应急系统启动
Emergency systems are now online
请遵行指令行动
Please follow indicated procedures
斯派德！
Spider!
能听到吗，斯派德？
Do you read me, Spider?
麦克斯，你在哪？
Max, where are you.
我脑袋里的东西
The thing in my head,
可以让所有人成为这里的公民，对吗？
it can make everyone a citizen here, right?
是的
Yeah.
你知道怎么弄，对吧？
You know how to get it out, right?
是
Yes.
你确定？
You're sure?
是的我确定
Yeah, I'm sure.
好，仔细听我说
OK, listen to me carefully.
选择军械库
Armory selected
好了
Set.
启动它
Turn me on.
好
OK.
克罗，去掉她俩
Crowe, get rid of those two.
乐意效劳，头儿 乐意效劳
My pleasure, boss. My pleasure.
臭小子你在哪？你在哪？
Where are you pikey? Where are you?
你好啊，小妞
How is it, girl?
我们来玩玩
Let's play.
来吧，我很温柔的，我保证
Come on, I'll be nice. Gentle, I promise
不 求你了
No. Please.
- 来吧  - 放开我！
- Come on. - Get off me!
- 想让我伤害你女儿吗？  - 不
- Want me to hurt the girl? - No.
到这来
Then come here.
妈的！
Fuck!
她还活着？
She alive?
现在还活着
For now.
呆在我后面
Stay behind me.
我带你离开这
I'm gonna get you out of here.
我有一个计划
I have a plan.
你听见我的声音了吗？
D'you hear that sound?
我来找你的声音
That's the sound of me coming for you
我将找到你 我会杀了你
I'll find you! I'll hunt you down!
弗蕾，我们得分开了
Frey, we have to split up.
- 什么？  - 听着
- What? - Listen.
你去地面上，带着这个
You're gonna go to the surface, OK? Take this.
这个房屋，给她治疗
Find a house, get her to a med-bay.
- 麦克斯，这不行  - 别停下，不要停…
- Max, it won't work. - Don't stop. Don't stop...
她没有身份
She doesn't have an ID.
这不管用
It doesn't work.
这次行
It will this time.
我知道怎么搞定
I know how to fix it.
- 选择地面  - 走
- Surface selected - Go.
和我一起
Come with me.
- 我随后就来  - 不
- I'm right behind you. - No.
我保证
I promise.
好吧，一位母亲和她女儿
Okay, a mother and her daughter
进了这个电梯
just went up in that elevator.
她们去地面找医疗舱
They're going to the surface headed for a med-bay.
让你的人确保他们安全到那
Send one of your guys make sure they get there.
我就会遵守协议
And we have our deal.
直接去医疗舱，伙计
Right to a med-bay, man.
- 我们走  - 走
- Let's go. - Let's go.
- 走快走！  - 这边！
- Go, go, go! - This way!
抓紧伙计
Hurry up, man.
启动紧急封锁…
emergency lock down...
快到了 快到了
Almost there. Almost there.
怎么了？
What's that?
这只是… 小伤！
It's just a m... bitch!
这才是对嘛
That's what I'm talking about.
侦测到火灾…
Fire has been detected...
开门啊！开门！
Hold the door! The Door!
将被关闭
have been shut down.
- 快点！快点！  - 走
- Come on! Come on! - Go, go, go
我们走！
Let's go!
该死 快走！
Fuck. C'mon!
走吧！你先来！快啊！
Let's go! You first. C'mon!
快点！起来！
Come on! Stand up!
起来！快起来！
Stand! Stand up! Come on!
起来！
Stand up!
你个小杂种
You little fucker.
我会把你的头拧下来！
I'm gonna take your fucking head off!
哥们，你现在必须站起来啊！
Dude, you should definitely stand up now!
不！
No!
呆着这吧
Stay there.
可恶！
Fuck!
你认为你能打过我吗？
You think you could get through me?
来啊，麦克斯！来啊！
Come on, Max! Come on!
我才刚刚开始
I'm just getting started.
来啊
Come on.
别放弃
Don't give up now.
起来，来啊！来！
Get up, come on! Come on!
你不止这些 我了解你的
You want more than this? I know you.
你看上去有点晕啊
You look a little bit dizzy, eh?
我弄伤你了吗？
Did I get you?
你在流血？你得去看看了
Are you bleeding? You must get that looked at.
嗨，伙计？
Hey, boy?
你想治好那个小姑娘吗？
You wanna heal that little girl?
你得先过我
You just need to come through me.
你还挺能打的
You got some fire in you, boy
你差点打败我
You almost had me.
我和你要同归于尽了
We die together, boy.
来吧，我们走
Come on, ma, let's go.
走，我们快走 快！
Let's go, man, let's do it. Come on!
好了，走
Ready? Let's go.
抓住那家伙
Get the guards, now!
好了
Alright.
抱歉
Sorry.
好的，我们开始，开始
OK, we're good, we're good.
我们开始了
We're good.
怎么了？
What?
麦克斯
Max.
没关系我知道
It's okay. I know.
这是不会恢复的
There's no coming back from this.
医疗舱也治不好
No med-bay can heal you.
好，把键盘给我
Alright, give it to me.
拿着
Take it.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
你只需按那个键
You just have to press that button.
弗蕾？
Frey?
麦克斯？麦克斯你在哪？
Max? Max where are you?
我不得不不遵守约定了
I'm gonna have to break my promise.
我不能过去你那里了
I can't make it back up there.
你记得我小时候说的吗？
You remember what I said when we were kids?
是的
Yes.
我将来总会有一天带大家去那
I'll take us there one day.
- 真的？  - 是的，我保证
- Really? - Yeah, I promise.
你不会相信我现在所看到的东西
You wouldn't believe what I'm looking at right now.
告诉玛蒂尔达，我很喜欢她的故事
Tell Matilda I really liked her story.
我明白河马为什么这么做了
I figured out why the Hippo did it.
来吧！
Come on!
抓我啊，来啊！
You go first. Come on!
我们都在做一些特殊的事情，麦克斯
We all have something special, Max.
有些事情注定去做
Something we're destined to do.
有些事情是生下来的使命
Something for which we were born.
系统重启
可恶！
Fuck you!
放开我！
Let go of me!
新公民：已加入
求你了，快点
Come on, please.
公民 M.桑地亚哥 女性
急性淋巴细胞白血病
已检测
再次原子化
我的宝贝，亲爱的
My baby. My dear.
解除，警官
Stand down, Officers.
逮捕他
Arrest him.
我不能逮捕极乐空间的居民
I can not arrest a citizen of Elysium.
什么？
What?
干的好
Doing a great job.
猜猜极乐空间现在属于谁了？
Guess who Elysium belongs to now?
新的公民需要医疗
计算中…
派遣医疗机去地球进行援救医疗
从我们这看过去那里很美不是吗？
从我这看过去那里也很美
现在它属于你了
你永远不要忘记你来自哪里
我的小麦克斯